[SPEAKER_01]: Mrs. Haines was there, and she had some real good stories.
[SPEAKER_03]: They added to it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Okay, now, would you tell me just how you happened to break into baseball, and when, and what it was like?
[SPEAKER_02]: I worked in the mine.
[SPEAKER_02]: I started working in the mine when I was 12 years old.
[SPEAKER_03]: In Shemokin?
[SPEAKER_03]: And where is Shemokin?
[SPEAKER_03]: Is it near Pittsburgh?
[SPEAKER_02]: It's between Harrisburg and Scranton.
[SPEAKER_02]: I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I picked coal there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had to have a handkerchief over my mouth.
[SPEAKER_02]: My wife talked about chewing.
[SPEAKER_02]: We had to chew the bag because the dust was so thick in here.
[SPEAKER_02]: These big screens separate this coal.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was all dry stuff.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you can imagine that dust from the
[SPEAKER_02]: And from down at Sarin, that's when I first started shooting back up.
[SPEAKER_02]: With a handkerchief over my mouth, from 6 o'clock in the morning, or 7 o'clock in the morning, till 6 o'clock at night.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's how long I worked.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know what salary I got?
[SPEAKER_02]: $3.75 a week.
[SPEAKER_02]: Could you join the Union?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, we had no union at that time.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was just, a union was just starting to build up.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, from picking slate where I got a job driving a mule on the Columbine, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I was there about a year or two.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then they gave me a job driving four mules hauling timber up in the mountains.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we have to saw it and drop it down in these holes in the miners, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that's where I started to throw rocks.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd see a bird or whatever I'd seen around, I'd pick up a rock and see what would hit it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, once in a while I did.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I got a habit of doing that thing.
[SPEAKER_02]: In my off times at home, I'd pick a lot of stones up in a can and tie a can on a tree someplace, and see how many times I could knock it off.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I could hit it pretty well.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that's when I think I got my control.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was throwing these rocks one time.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's a school teacher.
[SPEAKER_02]: He runs a school over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: He passed here every day.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he watched me throwing rocks and knocking these cans up his head, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: He called me and said, how about pitching for us?
[SPEAKER_02]: I was a sprinter, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: I was across from where I live, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, OK.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I pitched five games of ball that fall.
[SPEAKER_02]: I won all five.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you remember what year this would be?
[SPEAKER_02]: I was in 19... 7 or... 1908.
[SPEAKER_02]: 1908.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I won all them five ballgames.
[SPEAKER_02]: So, the next year, no, that same fall, I was in a movement picture place down there, me and my brother and another fella, and we come out and announce on the stage that Mr. Kowalewski's in the hospital, he's worn down at the box office.
[SPEAKER_02]: So...
[SPEAKER_02]: My brother looked at me, and I looked at him, and Frank Lewis looked at me, and I wonder what happened.
[SPEAKER_02]: Somebody must be sick, or something happened to Alex.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we go down there, and who was down there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Marty Hogan.
[SPEAKER_02]: He run the ball club, 19-9 for Lancaster.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he says, come on up to the hotel, and he says, I want to sign you up for a contract with Lancaster.
[SPEAKER_03]: What leg was Lancaster in then?
[SPEAKER_03]: In Tri-State.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a professional?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he was a professional.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we went to the hotel there, and he got this contract out, and I wouldn't sign it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, up to that time, I'm only getting $9 a week driving these four mules.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he looked at me and coaxed me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, hey, John.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, how about you sign it?
[SPEAKER_02]: That was my brother's.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a third baseman.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he said, Frank Lewis, I want you to sign too.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the only way they could get me to sign, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: So I signed up.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was never on a train in my life.
[SPEAKER_02]: I never was away from home.
[SPEAKER_03]: You're a little shy about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was shy about everything.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I went with the Lancaster.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I went with the Lancaster.
[SPEAKER_02]: When I come down here and I eat in the hotel, I was so shy.
[SPEAKER_02]: I used to walk out and go inside and eat hot dogs someplace.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was that terrible?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was so shabby?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's how bad I was.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, the season started, and a lot of these fellas there, only quite a few good ballplayers then.
[SPEAKER_02]: There was Roach, and Jack Deal, Fitzpatrick, and John.
[SPEAKER_02]: They all went to the big league, then next, like, oh, wait a minute.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I pitched.
[SPEAKER_02]: At first, he said, what do you want this kid for?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, I called Marty Hawkins.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, we'll just carry him on.
[SPEAKER_02]: My first league of the season, I won four ballgames, win the four ballgames for them.
[SPEAKER_02]: I won 31 ballgames and lose 11.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was 19-0.
[SPEAKER_03]: 19-9.
[SPEAKER_03]: Let me write that down here.
[SPEAKER_03]: 31-11.
[SPEAKER_03]: OK.
[SPEAKER_03]: Pitch any no-hitters?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I never looked for no-hitters.
[SPEAKER_02]: You got that on now?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: 1909 it was.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, 1909, Tony Mack picked me up in 1912.
[SPEAKER_03]: How about 1910-11?
[SPEAKER_02]: 1910-11, I was still with Lancaster.
[SPEAKER_02]: I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: In 1912, Tony Mack picked me up.
[SPEAKER_03]: How'd you do in those two years?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you remember?
[SPEAKER_03]: 10 or 11?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I went around all the time, but I couldn't go back and tell you how many games I won.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wonder why, did he know about you before 1912, those good records?
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you mind?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he had scouts over there, so he watched them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because Lancaster would have been not far from Philadelphia, you see.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he picked me up, and in the fall of the year, me and Joe Bush,
[SPEAKER_02]: We picked Cuba at the same time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was he with the same team?
[SPEAKER_02]: Was he with you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he joined me at the same time, the fall of 1912.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he pitched me.
[SPEAKER_02]: First game he pitched me, he pitched me against Detroit, in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_02]: I beat him three to nothing.
[SPEAKER_02]: I shut him out and gave him three hits.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was Cobb in that game?
[SPEAKER_03]: Cobb was in.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you get him out?
[SPEAKER_02]: Beach, Crawford.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you get Cobb out all right?
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I never had a trophy.
[SPEAKER_02]: As a matter of fact, I never had any trouble with good hitters.
[SPEAKER_02]: The ones that didn't get in trouble was bad hitters.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because I eased up on them.
[SPEAKER_02]: A good hitter, I worked with.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the reason of that, I never threw many balls at anybody.
[SPEAKER_02]: I made them hit every ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: My control, I said, why should I waste a ball?
[SPEAKER_02]: I got to pitch the next ball in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: But the stuff I had, I didn't have that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I pitched, many a time, I pitched three, four, five balls and retired a side, many times.
[SPEAKER_02]: They were told not to wait me on us and they waited me off the wall because I got too good a control.
[SPEAKER_03]: Throwing those rocks at the cans.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think that's what started me off.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think that's what started me.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because I noticed when I throw a rock at a can, you look at the can, I make my arm, I don't know, just like shooting a shotgun.
[SPEAKER_02]: I used to aim my, just the way I'd shoot, I'd aim my arm
[SPEAKER_02]: at this camp.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think that's what gave me the control.
[SPEAKER_03]: Where did the spitballs start?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, when Connie Mack left me go, you see, I went to Volcan, Washington.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, yeah, I went to Volcan, Washington for two years.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't use the spitballs.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was 13 and 14?
[SPEAKER_02]: That was 13 and 14.
[SPEAKER_03]: Why did they let you go?
[SPEAKER_03]: Why?
[SPEAKER_03]: He had a pretty good staff.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know who he had?
[SPEAKER_03]: Eddie Plank.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had Eddie Plank, Chief Vendor, Jack Coombs, Joe Bush.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had them.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't have much of a chance of that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, anyhow, from Spokane, I went to Portland.
[SPEAKER_02]: For 1915?
[SPEAKER_02]: For 1915.
[SPEAKER_02]: While I was in Portland, I just said to myself, I've got to get more stuff.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I heard Phil talk about a speed bomb, but I didn't know what it was.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't know how to throw it, so I just choked back a bit.
[SPEAKER_02]: I put a chunk of tobacco in and wet my fingers and threw it, but the tobacco was sticky, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was the partner?
[SPEAKER_02]: It was Joe McGinley.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Harry Krause, he come over to me and we could talk, and he said, you can't throw a spitball with tobacco.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, well, how'd you get out of them?
[SPEAKER_02]: And I said, what is that?
[SPEAKER_02]: And I said, I don't know what that is.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, you go in the drugstore, and he says, it comes in a bark.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he says, you cut just a little chunk off and put it in your mouth, and you get the juice out.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then I saw it this evening.
[SPEAKER_02]: The stars flew, and I could do it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I found out, when I was practicing this pit bull, I always pitched against the wind.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because that wind helped to break it down.
[SPEAKER_02]: That gave me a lot of confidence.
[SPEAKER_03]: And from there on, they... What if the wind was blowing the other way?
[SPEAKER_03]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, then, I had to take a good break all right, but a wooden break is good.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: There wasn't pitching down the winds.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the first thing I look when we come to a ball club.
[SPEAKER_02]: I always watch what where the wind is blowing.
[SPEAKER_03]: Of course, they have the big grandstand behind home plate.
[SPEAKER_03]: It kind of shields the wind.
[SPEAKER_03]: You wouldn't have much chance of the wind blowing.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, at the coast there, they only have one story.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, from there we were in the fall of the year.
[SPEAKER_02]: 1915.
[SPEAKER_02]: 1915, the fall of the year, we were winding up in Los Angeles.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the American League and National League always played an exhibition game in San Francisco, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: My colleague asked about a fellow, he said, we need a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who is the good pitcher out here?
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, we'll get Kowalewski.
[SPEAKER_02]: He looks like the best.
[SPEAKER_02]: So they informed me to Los Angeles if I'd come up and pitch for them.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, of course I'll come up and pitch for you, because I'm going to Los Angeles or San Francisco anyhow, because the World's Fair was on.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, it was after the season.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, well, you're too old to make my expense anyhow.
[SPEAKER_02]: When we started the game, Oscar Stannis catched me.
[SPEAKER_02]: After a football, a fat ball, a slow ball, he gave me a spitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: I threw a spitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: He hit his glove in the end, and he walked out to me, and he said, be careful.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, what's the matter?
[SPEAKER_02]: I missed a sign?
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: So from that time on,
[SPEAKER_02]: Every ball player in the American National League wanted me.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, with all the different kind of ball players there.
[SPEAKER_02]: When they seen what I had, now they couldn't even hit it.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's how good I was.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who was Stanage with?
[SPEAKER_03]: Which team then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, Detroit.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he was Detroit.
[SPEAKER_03]: But how'd Cleveland get you then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, Cleveland owned Portland.
[SPEAKER_03]: So Cleveland... Did his fellow McReady run Portland?
[SPEAKER_02]: McReady, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Walter McReady.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did he have anything to do with Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, they had a contract between both, I think they did.
[SPEAKER_02]: Anyhow, we're in New Orleans, see, I'm with Cleveland, and we're playing New York, I believe.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we were in a hardball club, and the New Orleans hardball club was the ones that fought to play, you see.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Jack Dobbs, Jack Dobbs,
[SPEAKER_02]: He needed a pitch.
[SPEAKER_02]: He came on and asked Lee Foley.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, Lee, how about on the Kowalewski lane?
[SPEAKER_02]: So Lee asked.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, sure.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll go on the pitch.
[SPEAKER_02]: Here's one I thought, well, here's one I'm going to be left in the morning.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I went in there for five innings, thinking that we'd hit a ball out of the infield.
[SPEAKER_02]: So Lee walked over and said, that's enough for him.
[SPEAKER_02]: So Jimmy and Doug, the way they listened to them stories, I heard, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: So Johnny Depp said, you leave Kowalewski here, I'm like a good pitcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, he's a good pitcher indeed.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a New Orleans manager, or?
[SPEAKER_02]: He managed.
[SPEAKER_03]: New Orleans, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: How was your last year, how was your year in Portland there in 1915?
[SPEAKER_03]: How'd you do there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, listen.
[SPEAKER_02]: I must have been in about 70 or 80 balls.
[SPEAKER_02]: I only went 17, but I must have been in 80 balls.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I don't know how many I went for big and bottom and lush.
[SPEAKER_02]: And there were three pitchers there to go about four or five in, and they were done, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: So they'd say, come on, it's been me.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did your arm get tired?
[SPEAKER_03]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you get tired?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've never seen it get tired.
[SPEAKER_03]: Rubber arm.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've never had a sore arm.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I never, all I ever got was two days rest in the Olympic League.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's all I wanted, because if I had three or four days, I'm too wild.
[SPEAKER_02]: I go out there, I'm too fast, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm trying to throw a bomb.
[SPEAKER_02]: Or, in other words, I just throw half the balls.
[SPEAKER_02]: Why should I throw six, seven, nine balls of powder, and I can throw two or three?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's how I save myself all the time.
[SPEAKER_03]: I interviewed Leroy Parmalee yesterday.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, just the reverse, he couldn't get the ball over the plate.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that was why his career was so short.
[SPEAKER_03]: He could throw hard, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: And at that time, listen, you had to get that ball over because everybody choked up.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: You'd take the righty, he'd stand up.
[SPEAKER_02]: Take a fellow with control today.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had to make the best pitch in the world.
[SPEAKER_02]: If he has control, one of them fellows will stand back there and end the bat.
[SPEAKER_03]: How many spitball pitchers were there in the American League?
[SPEAKER_02]: Very many.
[SPEAKER_02]: Me.
[SPEAKER_02]: Carl Mays.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, Mays wasn't.
[SPEAKER_03]: Mays wasn't.
[SPEAKER_03]: Carl Mays.
[SPEAKER_02]: There was about five, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: What did you think when they abolished the... Of course, it didn't affect you.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, it wouldn't affect me.
[SPEAKER_03]: But what did you people that threw the spitball, what did you think about that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't see why they ever took it out.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's what I say, the roots.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Ruth had to hit it in, all that stuff.
[SPEAKER_02]: A black ball, spit ball, emery ball, knuckle ball, shine ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had to hit it in.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then still, he'd keep a ball in there for maybe two or three games before he'd take it out.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you like to use a ball that was pretty well worn?
[SPEAKER_03]: Was that easier to...
[SPEAKER_02]: It didn't make any difference, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: It didn't make any difference.
[SPEAKER_02]: What I used to watch, if I got a ball and there was a scratch on it, you could make that ball sail any way you wanted to make it sail.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, at the tray, I see the, the minute they look at the ball, they throw it out.
[SPEAKER_00]: What's a black ball?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: A lot of liquid in the back of your hand.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just wondered.
[SPEAKER_02]: They're black and rubber.
[SPEAKER_03]: The emery balls where you had a little piece of sandpaper in your glove, is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, they'd have in the belt.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just scratch it.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's always just one thing.
[SPEAKER_02]: The shine ball, you fill the seams with paracene, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: A little dirt on there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you shine the other part up.
[SPEAKER_02]: All balance of the ball, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: And if you know how a ball is all balanced, you can make a curve any way you want to make a curve.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just like, say, you see a scratch on a ball, you can make that ball go any way you want to make it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Seems funny, but you can do it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tricks and trades.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did your catchers have much trouble catching your spinner?
[SPEAKER_03]: Any of your catchers, or it's a hard pitch to catch?
[SPEAKER_02]: I seen Stephen Heeler one time in Washington.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sam Rice gets up and gets a triple off me, first man.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I strike the next three men out, and Stephen Heeler never held a ball in his hand.
[SPEAKER_02]: I hit him all over.
[SPEAKER_02]: Second hands, the first fellow gets up and gets a double off me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I strike the next two out, and the other fellow popped out.
[SPEAKER_02]: And this speaker came in, and he says, hell, he said, if you can't catch him, he says, I'll put somebody else in there, catch him.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that's how good I was that day.
[SPEAKER_02]: If I had to put the speed on everything, I could pick that ball any way I wanted to.
[SPEAKER_03]: How often did you throw the spitter?
[SPEAKER_02]: Not very often, but you always look for it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, that was part of the value of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: If you're looking for a spitball, and you're throwing fastball,
[SPEAKER_02]: You got them all balanced.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: What would the spitball do that made it so hard to hit?
[SPEAKER_03]: Or was it the fact that...
[SPEAKER_02]: Listen, spitball is no different than a knuckleball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, you've seen what a knuckleball... You know a good knuckleball, you can't catch.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's the same with spitball.
[SPEAKER_02]: I reverse the ball, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: When I let go, you...
[SPEAKER_02]: If I throw a ball, it'll naturally go out this way.
[SPEAKER_02]: I throw a ball, I held it back with my thumb, and it went off its way.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just reversed.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you have, did anybody teach you the fine art of pitching?
[SPEAKER_03]: Or as you came up, like Connie Mack, would he give you a few tips?
[SPEAKER_02]: I had four brothers, all ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_02]: Harry, he was a Detroit.
[SPEAKER_02]: Frank, he joined the Union League in Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a pitcher too, but he got movement in and went out.
[SPEAKER_02]: John, he was tried out with Philadelphia, and he was with Lancaster.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Jake, the older brother, well, he was a pitcher, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't know much about him, because, you know, I was too young then.
[SPEAKER_02]: But there's no one that never asked me or never told me how to do this, how to do that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I picked myself.
[SPEAKER_03]: There were five brothers?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Five of you.
[SPEAKER_03]: What did your parents think about this?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did they like to have you play ball, or did they not really?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, we used to get held because we'd tear up too many shoes.
[SPEAKER_03]: Tear up too many shoes?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: There wasn't much money at that time, they couldn't afford buying shoes all the time.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did your parents marry here, or did they come from... No, they married here.
[SPEAKER_03]: Where'd they come from, and when?
[SPEAKER_03]: Poland.
[SPEAKER_03]: When did they come over, you remember?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I couldn't.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's too far back for me.
[SPEAKER_03]: But they were married before they came here.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were all you boys born here?
[SPEAKER_02]: All born, all born in the Fiddler.
[SPEAKER_02]: Only a little bit of a patch outside of Smokin', but a dozen homes here.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the name of the...
[SPEAKER_02]: There was only about 12 homes there.
[SPEAKER_02]: There was a breaker there, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: A coal mine breaker there.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was a fiddler, then they called his house the fiddler.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that how your parents happened to settle there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Because of the coal mines?
[SPEAKER_03]: I think so, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: I thought that was largely Irish.
[SPEAKER_03]: Weren't there a lot of Irish there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, the Irish is up in Locust Gap.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's a little far too.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were there many... That was all Irish.
[SPEAKER_03]: Were there many Polish people in your community?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh yeah, quite a few.
[SPEAKER_03]: Were you from this area at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: From Smokin.
[SPEAKER_03]: Were you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, you two met in Smokin?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: You're Polish, right?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: You were rather unusual being a Polish person playing big league ball, or there weren't too many at this time?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did anybody make remarks about this at all?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: There was a few Polish fellows there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he changed his name.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, Simansky, he was Simansky.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: Joe Boling.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bolinsky, he was Joe Bolinsky.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, who managed, Lee Fole managed when you came up at Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: What kind of manager was Lee Fole to play for?
[SPEAKER_02]: I think it was a smart manager.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think he's a good manager.
[SPEAKER_02]: But then they got Speaker to come over from Boston, and Speaker took him to next year's thing.
[SPEAKER_03]: How was Tris as a manager?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, like all the rest, they got a good ball club.
[SPEAKER_02]: You're going to win.
[SPEAKER_02]: If you ain't got a good ball club, you're going to lose.
[SPEAKER_03]: Isn't it kind of hard for a center fielder to manage the club?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: He asked for help, like, you know, sit on the bench.
[SPEAKER_02]: Something had come up, but he couldn't figure it out a lot of the way.
[SPEAKER_02]: He asked for help, what he should do and what he shouldn't do.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a good man to work for, a really good man to work for.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was that a pretty closely-knit team there in 1920, where there was a pretty good spirit in the players?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah, there was a good spirit.
[SPEAKER_02]: Everybody went there.
[SPEAKER_02]: They would never win.
[SPEAKER_03]: How about the Ray Chapman incident?
[SPEAKER_03]: Were you at that game?
[SPEAKER_02]: I pitched that game.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was killed in New York.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was killed in New York, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I know.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I pitched that ball game.
[SPEAKER_03]: How did that incident, how did it, you, what did you think happened then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, we just stopped, we were like some, you know, other people, and get hit, and knocked out, and make them out another, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: But they took them out in a stretcher and on, and the next morning at five o'clock, they were already dead.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, it was a feeling towards Mays.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, it's... Of course, they didn't like him anyhow, but after that...
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm not saying much about Mays.
[SPEAKER_03]: You don't like him, huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't think he was...
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll tell you, he was a hard man to hit, and I'll tell you why.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a darn good fast ball, and a good curve, and both underhanded.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you didn't know which way it was going to break, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't think he tried to hit him, but I know at that time, we'd see a fellow get enough too close, we'd fire under his chin.
[SPEAKER_02]: Get him out of there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Under his chin?
[SPEAKER_02]: Close to him, anyhow, see.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, but you had good control, though.
[SPEAKER_03]: Some of those people didn't.
[SPEAKER_03]: Like Parmerly, Parmerly actually said he had five people in the head in his career.
[SPEAKER_03]: He couldn't pitch after that because it unnerved him so.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't believe I hit a dozen people all the time I was in baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, Roger Peckinpah played second base for the Yankees that day, and he says he saw that pitch, the underhand pitch, come in and up, and he says, it was right over the plate.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Chappie apparently leaned over the plate.
[SPEAKER_02]: He must have just frozen.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's too bad.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's nobody going in there and saying, I'm going to kill you, I'm going to hit you.
[SPEAKER_02]: He wouldn't try to chase you away from there.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, they got too close.
[SPEAKER_03]: But maybe it might get away from you when you're trying to chase them away.
[SPEAKER_02]: Could it do that?
[SPEAKER_02]: It could get away from them, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: Should they have been wearing helmets?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: You don't think they should wear helmets?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I think now, I think, I thought you said... Well, maybe they should have, then.
[SPEAKER_03]: Maybe they should have.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, if they had them on me, they'd probably see him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I think he was one of the greatest, well, that you ever seen.
[SPEAKER_02]: Fast.
[SPEAKER_02]: I seen him in Cleveland one time.
[SPEAKER_03]: What do you mean now?
[SPEAKER_02]: Chapman.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: I seen him in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: They were running a race.
[SPEAKER_02]: They had a lot of these racers, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I asked, who do you ask Chapman to run a race?
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ah, come on, they coax him.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Chapman was out here with spikes and everything, and these fellas don't have spikes.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I don't know how far he beat everyone.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was really fast.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, he was fast.
[SPEAKER_03]: And a pretty good hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, a fair hitter, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And a good fielder.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he was a good baller.
[SPEAKER_02]: Good arm and everything else.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, didn't that pretty well upset the team?
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, here you're leading the league, and you fight for a pennant, and you lose your stuff.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, we didn't fight for the pennant.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sure stuff.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, then he talked about Joe Sewell and Tom
[SPEAKER_02]: south and he finally got Joe, but Joe wasn't near the ball players.
[SPEAKER_02]: Joe had a lot of hitters, but they didn't mark him up to them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh?
[SPEAKER_03]: How do you mean?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, his ball hit to him, they either gave it to the hitter or the hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: I wonder why.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had some friends up in the press box.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a young fella and we didn't want to discourage him.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was up to the...
[SPEAKER_03]: When he first came up.
[SPEAKER_03]: I talked to Luke Sewell.
[SPEAKER_03]: I interviewed him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you know Luke pretty well?
[SPEAKER_03]: Luke?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Luke Sewell.
[SPEAKER_02]: We got a card from him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think we did.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, we did.
[SPEAKER_02]: At Christmas time.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's at Akron.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's over here in Ohio sometime.
[SPEAKER_03]: Akron.
[SPEAKER_03]: I just talked to him about a month or so ago.
[SPEAKER_03]: He told about coming up there.
[SPEAKER_03]: He missed the World Series, of course, since Canton 21.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he had a lot of good stories to tell.
[SPEAKER_03]: So tell me about your brother, Harry.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I can't tell you nothing if you ask him questions.
[SPEAKER_00]: He doesn't know enough to ask you questions.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's a pretty good pitcher, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was older.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was the one with the Phillies?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, with the Phillies, and then with the Detroit.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, well, tell me, he won three games in the World Series, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, he won three games in the... Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He beat Chris Hemsworth.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it's the only three games that Philadelphia beat New York all that year.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the way I understand it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, the only three guys in Philadelphia beat him all that year.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now he was through in the big league before you came up, is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he give you any?
[SPEAKER_02]: In 1909 he went to Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_02]: Detroit?
[SPEAKER_02]: Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's where he beat New York in 1909.
[SPEAKER_03]: I thought that was 1908.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, 1908 I was there.
[SPEAKER_02]: It might have been 19, but I'm sure it was 19.
[SPEAKER_03]: He beat Mathewson, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh boy, that must have been something.
[SPEAKER_03]: What was his... do you remember how many games he won?
[SPEAKER_02]: I know he won once in Philadelphia in deep, but I know he won over 20 games.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did he give you any encouragement when you came up?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: No?
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess they didn't encourage each other.
[SPEAKER_02]: When I came up and I was going to Detroit, he'd get off the bench and go down the bullpen or something.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know how you razzle another one.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't even want to hear all that stuff again.
[SPEAKER_03]: You never pitched against each other.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, we were five in an exhibition game in Lancaster one time on this plane.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the only time.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I don't blame him for not pitching to him.
[SPEAKER_02]: If I went in there and beat him, you know what he'd have said?
[SPEAKER_02]: He laid down.
[SPEAKER_02]: He wanted me to win.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's true.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's a lot of people that thought that.
[SPEAKER_02]: People that say that.
[SPEAKER_02]: He laid down.
[SPEAKER_02]: He wanted me to win.
[SPEAKER_02]: This way, Detroit beat me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was the first game winner.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they beat my game three and two with 12 wins, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, if Harry was in there, I know, because
[SPEAKER_02]: Craig would always beat Harry things, always hit him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I wouldn't have got no credit for it anyway.
[SPEAKER_03]: What was his best pitch?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, he had curveball, fastball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was his control as good as yours?
[SPEAKER_02]: He had good control, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, about your other brothers, did any of them get to the big time?
[SPEAKER_02]: John, why, he went to Philadelphia now, I told you, with Connie Mack.
[SPEAKER_02]: Eddie Collins, being a mother of a child, preferred base with Connie Mack.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did he play much?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, he was only there, and then they beat him out, and he sent him out to the coast someplace, in Muscat, in the center of there, I think, in the center.
[SPEAKER_02]: So from that on, you know how they fade away, you know how the ballpark would fade away.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then the others?
[SPEAKER_02]: And Frank, he joined the Union League when it started in Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_03]: The Federal League, maybe?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, the Union League.
[SPEAKER_02]: There was a Third League coming at that time.
[SPEAKER_03]: So he got wounded.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's quite a baseball family.
[SPEAKER_03]: How did you happen to be
[SPEAKER_03]: How did you leave Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_03]: You went to Washington in 24, 25.
[SPEAKER_03]: What happened?
[SPEAKER_02]: I slept a little bit over there, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: I only went 13 ballgames.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was your arm sore at all?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: What happened?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had to make a change.
[SPEAKER_02]: They got three ballers from these players.
[SPEAKER_02]: I figured they were getting a good trailer.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then they went in the pennant with you over there.
[SPEAKER_03]: You had the best percentage in the league, I like that here.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you get everything?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you just have a good year?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did everything come back?
[SPEAKER_02]: Just had a good year.
[SPEAKER_02]: So, the next year, I started out, and the first thing I knew, my arm dropped.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know if it didn't hurt me or not.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd go and pitch about two or three in, and it still dropped.
[SPEAKER_02]: Didn't know what the heck it was.
[SPEAKER_02]: Everybody thought, well, I'm done, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: So I went to one set of reefs in Youngstown.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, there's nothing the matter with your arm.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, by God.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, I'll pitch it one or two ends.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, it'll fall down.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, I don't care.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's nothing the matter with your arm.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I went to Old Anne Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: They let me go.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I went to a dentist.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had bad teeth, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: And he said, Kobe, the wonder you're on.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, that poison's been in your system for a long time.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he said, well, get your teeth out.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, you get your teeth out of there, and you're on.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll come back.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll just quit.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't bother that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't try.
[SPEAKER_02]: But that's what it was.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's all this moisture from your teeth, that bad
[SPEAKER_03]: How was Bucky Harris as a manager?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, he was a nice manager.
[SPEAKER_02]: I liked Bucky as a manager.
[SPEAKER_03]: Why was this?
[SPEAKER_03]: Why was he so nice?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I liked him as well.
[SPEAKER_02]: There are some managers that get rough and everything else, but I've never seen him get rough, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: He knew how to handle...
[SPEAKER_02]: If somebody pulled a bad play or anything, some manager gets rough on them, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you get rough on them.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that's something they couldn't do with me.
[SPEAKER_02]: They couldn't call me down or anything, because I couldn't stand it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I didn't like anybody cursing.
[SPEAKER_03]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did anybody ever try to ball you out, or?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I was never balled out.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, you pitched.
[SPEAKER_03]: They didn't have much opportunity to.
[SPEAKER_02]: I know when I joined Connie Maddox.
[SPEAKER_02]: And after the game of Mione's, that's the hotel, you know?
[SPEAKER_02]: And if he had something to say to you, he wouldn't tell him.
[SPEAKER_02]: He just didn't take a walk with him.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he'd explain it like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I never seen him calling with him on the bench.
[SPEAKER_02]: He'd always, after a game, he'd just take him a walk with him and explain to him and tell him.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was a nice way of doing it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not being a crowd.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, when did you get married?
[SPEAKER_01]: In 22, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: I even forgot.
[SPEAKER_03]: Shame on you.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was married to my sister.
[SPEAKER_01]: And she passed away.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they had two boys.
[SPEAKER_03]: And when were they married?
[SPEAKER_02]: 1915.
[SPEAKER_02]: Or 1914.
[SPEAKER_01]: 1914.
[SPEAKER_01]: So when she passed away, I took care of the children.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, my.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know how much money I had when I got married?
[SPEAKER_02]: $80.
[SPEAKER_03]: You were out with playing ball on the West Coast.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I wasn't out there yet.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm just joining.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, I'll get married in 14.
[SPEAKER_02]: We got married at $80.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just said, why don't I go get some money?
[SPEAKER_02]: I just wrote the appointment right away.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, I need money.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, how much do you need?
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, a couple hundred dollars.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, them days and these days are two different things.
[SPEAKER_03]: What was life like in the Pacific Coast League in those years?
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, the way you traveled, the places you stayed, the kind of food they ate, what was life like?
[SPEAKER_02]: We traveled.
[SPEAKER_03]: By bus or train?
[SPEAKER_02]: By train, mostly.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the food is slow.
[SPEAKER_02]: They give you all you want?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, what you paid for a steak now, you get one third.
[SPEAKER_02]: You get a steak for about 50 cents.
[SPEAKER_02]: You get a good meal for less than a dollar.
[SPEAKER_03]: How about the hotels you stayed in?
[SPEAKER_02]: They have a nice hotel, but we don't.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's something we never bothered with, because all that was paid with a lot of clubs, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: The meetings were paid by the clubs and that thing.
[SPEAKER_03]: When you were in Portland, you had to find, did you stay in a rooming house there with a couple of players?
[SPEAKER_03]: I stayed in a rooming house.
[SPEAKER_03]: A couple of players?
[SPEAKER_02]: The apartment I had.
[SPEAKER_03]: What kind of a ballpark did they have in Portland?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, they had a nice ballpark.
[SPEAKER_02]: I liked their ballpark.
[SPEAKER_03]: Pretty good size, good facilities there, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then what did you do in the off-season when you weren't playing ball?
[SPEAKER_02]: Come home and go to the mountains, hunting.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's where you got those deer heads.
[SPEAKER_03]: Where would you hunt?
[SPEAKER_03]: Mountains or water?
[SPEAKER_02]: Pennsylvania.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a camp there, didn't we?
[SPEAKER_02]: We had a camp close to Fort George, New York.
[SPEAKER_02]: Joe Woods, Elmer Smith, Lee, and Joe.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I've interviewed Elmer Smith.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've talked to Elmer Smith over in Cleveland, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, we had a camp.
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess Elmer Woods still uses that camp.
[SPEAKER_03]: You and Elmer Smith and Joe Woods had a camp there, didn't they?
[SPEAKER_02]: Me and Joe, Elmer Smith, Ed Klepper, Joe Harris.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, you keep this year around?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, he can take care of it all.
[SPEAKER_02]: I haven't been up there for years.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's got a summer home up there, see.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now this is Show Low?
[SPEAKER_03]: Where is this?
[SPEAKER_03]: Show Low or?
[SPEAKER_02]: Show Low Falls.
[SPEAKER_03]: Show Low Falls.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now where is that?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's in the mountains of Pennsylvania.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that near Scranton?
[SPEAKER_02]: You know where Bloomingdale's Club is?
[SPEAKER_02]: Who?
[SPEAKER_02]: Bloomingdale's Club, a millionaire's club in New York.
[SPEAKER_01]: God, they'll look it up in a minute.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kate Smith had lived out there, didn't she, Sam?
[SPEAKER_02]: Kate Smith, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: She lived above Shehola.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Between Shehola and Harcourt, or Harcourt.
[SPEAKER_02]: She was living around.
[SPEAKER_03]: And you'd go up there after the season?
[SPEAKER_02]: After the season was over, before the season was started.
[SPEAKER_02]: Nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you didn't have to have her rest.
[SPEAKER_03]: Keep in shape that way, huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you have any problem keeping in shape?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: When I lived, there weren't a day that I wouldn't run over the mountains.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd walk warm.
[SPEAKER_02]: All winter, I didn't care if it hit the snow.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd walk out about two, three miles.
[SPEAKER_02]: When I'd get out there, I'd jog all the way home.
[SPEAKER_02]: When I'd go in spring training, I was in perfect shape all the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd set a new one.
[SPEAKER_02]: All I'd do is get my arm in shape.
[SPEAKER_03]: What was your playing weight, about?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, 175.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just about a hundred and seventy-five.
[SPEAKER_03]: How long did it take you to get that arm in shape?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, it didn't take long.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you think spring training is too long these days?
[SPEAKER_02]: You're asking about modern baseball?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I know I could get in shape in at least two weeks.
[SPEAKER_02]: At least two weeks.
[SPEAKER_01]: How long do they have?
[SPEAKER_03]: They have about a month or so, and the pictures come a couple weeks before that.
[SPEAKER_03]: You get ready.
[SPEAKER_01]: Look at the gloves they had today.
[SPEAKER_03]: Where were some of the spring training camps you went to?
[SPEAKER_02]: What were some of the places you went?
[SPEAKER_03]: New Orleans.
[SPEAKER_02]: New Orleans.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said nobody could miss Walter Baffin.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's true.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's true.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you travel with him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Not all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was the two boys going to school.
[SPEAKER_03]: When would you go with him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, when he was close to home, close to Smokin.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not that he didn't want me out, but I can't depend.
[SPEAKER_01]: Those children have to go to school.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I didn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, if he was in Philadelphia, New York, then we'd go down.
[SPEAKER_01]: Washington, D.C., we went down.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you like baseball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I liked it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I liked to watch it.
[SPEAKER_01]: They used to say, well, he can't hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: What are they putting him on?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, what are you telling me that for?
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't know who I was.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't get along.
[SPEAKER_01]: So one time I said, I bet he's going to hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not knowing no more than the man in the room.
[SPEAKER_01]: So luck he hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I did that guy one push in the back.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, what did you say about that guy?
[SPEAKER_01]: So he says to me, you must have had a bet on him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I says, I sure did.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, we had our own seats, but he used to always like to go someplace else.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd learn more, you know, here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did the boys like it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: The boys liked it, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: How did you feel when he was pitching?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, Atalia, sometimes I was nervous.
[SPEAKER_03]: You were more nervous than he was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he wasn't nervous at all.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's not nervous today, and I'm the nervous one.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you recall any particular big thrill you had watching him pitch?
[SPEAKER_03]: Anything stand out in your mind?
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't go to when he won the World Series.
[SPEAKER_03]: You didn't go?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, dear.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was a bad time of year to get away, probably, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Sure.
[SPEAKER_03]: How'd you feel about that World Series, winning all those games?
[SPEAKER_02]: It didn't bother me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just said to myself, if he gets me a few runs, I'll give him a bad one.
[SPEAKER_03]: How did you happen to pitch so much?
[SPEAKER_03]: We had Bagby over there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Wasn't there anybody else?
[SPEAKER_03]: Males?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, males, he'd come in on the coast.
[SPEAKER_02]: He'd come in on the coast.
[SPEAKER_03]: What did the speaker say to you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it was the second game.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, I'm working you today.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I said, it looks like I'm going to have two days rest.
[SPEAKER_02]: And when you lay back, next time.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, OK, I can pitch every day.
[SPEAKER_02]: It made no difference to me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know why it is, but I didn't have to warn them much.
[SPEAKER_02]: I bet you if I had 5, 6, 8, 10 balls, you might be warned.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I never cut into the ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know what I mean?
[SPEAKER_02]: I never forced myself throwing them in there, unless I had to.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell them about the 19 innings you pitched one time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: I pitched 19 in New York one time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Up to the 8th in, there were 9 hits off me.
[SPEAKER_02]: And from the 9th in to the 19th, I think I had only 3 hits.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: So you see the difference in pitching.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you win?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I beat him 2 to 1.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did the other pitcher pitch the whole game?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: You did though, the complete game?
[SPEAKER_02]: I pitched the whole 19 in.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was looking through the record, you've pitched about a few hundred complete games.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was very few times ever taken out of there, I know that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I know when I start, I bring you in, because there's never many around, you'll know it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Occasions take me out.
[SPEAKER_03]: I bet the games were pretty fast when you pitched.
[SPEAKER_02]: I pitched a game in St. Louis one time, and he said, we have to catch a train out in the stockyard someplace.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that game was played less than an hour.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: A nine inning game?
[SPEAKER_02]: Nine inning game, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, you know, if you take it that time, you take a picture, they all had control.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't care who, you, you, and the gang had control.
[SPEAKER_02]: Every, every ball club had at least two good pitchers in Australia, and I had a couple, but... How long did that 19 inning game take, do you know?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: Probably not more than two and a half hours or so.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: It'd take five hours to play that today.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who was, there must have been some hitter which gave you some trouble though, wasn't there anybody?
[SPEAKER_02]: You take these hitters at show clubs, they give them more trouble than anybody.
[SPEAKER_02]: They're standing right on that plate, and you have to get that ball over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now you take Ruth, and then he stood a little farther away.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now you take Cobb.
[SPEAKER_02]: I never had any trouble with Cobb.
[SPEAKER_03]: How'd you pitch him?
[SPEAKER_02]: Fast ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Would it be inside?
[SPEAKER_02]: Because Cobb is a fella, he hit left field all the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: The longest field where he could be any mile, he was fast.
[SPEAKER_02]: He'd bury someone and pull the ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he couldn't push this inside ball that side.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he didn't go by.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd strike him once or twice every time I'd be in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Ruth, all the time, they kept it outside and kept it down low.
[SPEAKER_02]: They couldn't get a hold of it.
[SPEAKER_03]: How about Joe Jackson?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, he left here while I got over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: He left even then.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, but you pitched against him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I pitched.
[SPEAKER_03]: How was he to pitch against him?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I never associated too much with other players.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was always by myself.
[SPEAKER_03]: Didn't this bother your pitching?
[SPEAKER_03]: Your drinking, or you didn't mix them, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't mix them.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got drunk.
[SPEAKER_02]: One time, my brother came over, a craven, him and another fellow, and they were there two days and I didn't pitch.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, well, I'll probably pitch tomorrow.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, I'll take us out.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I pitched tomorrow.
[SPEAKER_02]: The next day, I took them out.
[SPEAKER_02]: I took them across the river in Cleveland, across that river bridge there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some police district down there.
[SPEAKER_02]: What's 25th Street?
[SPEAKER_02]: Moonshine, right there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Listen, I was a drunk.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know why I'd be able to come to Euclid Alabama.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd better knock down two or three safety zones.
[SPEAKER_02]: And nobody stopped me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I went in the hotel near the garage on the bottom.
[SPEAKER_02]: I go in there, and I had to take my car to the second story.
[SPEAKER_02]: I took it up there, and when I came out, I told my brother, and I said, walk straight through.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, somebody might see us.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm drunker than anyone.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I go up in the room.
[SPEAKER_02]: I go up in the room.
[SPEAKER_02]: The next morning, I get up good and early,
[SPEAKER_02]: I got on the phone, I called the ball club up.
[SPEAKER_02]: No one was out there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I told them this is exactly what happened.
[SPEAKER_02]: I told them everything.
[SPEAKER_02]: So when I went out and the speaker came in, the whole meeting in the morning, he said, there were phone calls up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, the hell with it.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I took care of myself.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't want to go out and have a couple of drinks today.
[SPEAKER_02]: It didn't bother me any.
[SPEAKER_03]: You look pretty good.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I never drunk before a ball game, you know what I mean.
[SPEAKER_03]: As long as you were all ready to go and you were pitching.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was ready to pitch any time of the day.
[SPEAKER_02]: Many a time I had a notion to go from the bench right out of the box.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some pitchers in there getting empty.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know why I did, but my arm was never sore.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got tired, you know what I mean?
[SPEAKER_03]: That's why you're in the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, that's quite a record there.
[SPEAKER_03]: When did you first hear about being elected to the Hall of Fame?
[SPEAKER_03]: Mrs. O'Connor, you asked her when she came in here.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, Mrs. Haynes told us that, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, she was the one that gave the story.
[SPEAKER_02]: She gave you that story.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do your boys live here in town?
[SPEAKER_00]: Do your boys live here?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he lives here in Western Avenue.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's been with Sears, you know, for 28 years, taking care of our television down there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Tell me, how did you happen to relocate here in South Bend?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, they had an amateur ball club here, and they had a good...
[SPEAKER_03]: They offered me a good salary, and I came out here.
[SPEAKER_03]: An amateur club offered you a salary?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, if I was going to name a bachelor or a runner, it wasn't an amateur.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a...
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know what he liked ball for, no league or anything, just... just a boring summer.
[SPEAKER_02]: So...
[SPEAKER_02]: When was this?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, my...
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, thank you.
[SPEAKER_02]: After I was through with Washington.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: So you came here to play baseball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know if you want a glass.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, that's fine.
[SPEAKER_03]: Thank you so much.
[SPEAKER_01]: You want a shot, Pop?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, you know I want a shot.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you didn't bring him one.
[SPEAKER_00]: Shame on you.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, well, have you lived in Shamokin all these years?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I come right out here in 28.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, up until then, you went back to Shamokin every year?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Up to that time, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Your home was there until 28 or 29 you came here.
[SPEAKER_03]: I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: What did you do then, after you played ball here?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you do anything else?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had a filling station here.
[SPEAKER_02]: A filling station?
[SPEAKER_02]: These darn things.
[SPEAKER_02]: And depression-wise, I couldn't even let it go.
[SPEAKER_02]: There was no gasoline to buy or anything else, and I had to get rid of that.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I just laid it on since that time.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't do nothing since.
[SPEAKER_03]: Have you had this house since then?
[SPEAKER_03]: Have you always been in this house here?
[SPEAKER_00]: Didn't Jess Haines have a gas station?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, in a garage house.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had a gas station.
[SPEAKER_03]: Jess Haines had one.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jess Haines had one, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, but didn't he fresh it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Sure, he wants it strong, the rascal.
[SPEAKER_02]: Look.
[SPEAKER_02]: You want me to split it?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, you ask her.
[SPEAKER_02]: You ask her about the whole thing.
[SPEAKER_03]: We wanted to ask you about when you first heard of his election to the Hall of Fame and the reaction to that one.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went to that phone, and it was Ford Frick that called.
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, is Stanley home?
[SPEAKER_01]: I says, no, he's not, he's fishing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he says, I may as well break the news to you.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he says to me, he says, I want to congratulate Kogi for being elected into the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I swear to heaven, I couldn't talk for the second or two.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when I did come to my senses, I said, well, I think it's about time.
[SPEAKER_01]: So when I met the man up in Cooperstown, he came over to the table, and that was the first I met him, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he says to Colby, he says, I'm going to cause that woman a heart attack.
[SPEAKER_01]: I says, and how?
[SPEAKER_01]: So every time he sees me, he's kidding me.
[SPEAKER_01]: But, oh, I'm telling you, after that, I really cried.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he comes home from fishing, and I'm on pins and needles, when is he going to come home?
[SPEAKER_01]: So when he come home, I didn't tell him right away, after a bit, and I said, you know what, Colby, we had a telephone call from Forge Creek.
[SPEAKER_01]: What for?
[SPEAKER_01]: Like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, well, he wanted to be the first to congratulate you.
[SPEAKER_01]: You were elected to the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I hate to tell you this.
[SPEAKER_01]: You ain't got that thing going, have you?
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, oh, shit.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, no, that's true.
[SPEAKER_01]: So pretty soon when the telephones start moving, oh, one after another, boys, old boys, no more sat down until it started going again.
[SPEAKER_01]: But honest, I couldn't read it, neither could he.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I had to get it off my chest.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I made the, I told him up at Cooperstown, I says, remember, if he'd have been gone,
[SPEAKER_01]: I says, it would have been a waste of time to tell me that you want.
[SPEAKER_01]: I says, I wouldn't have even came to get them.
[SPEAKER_01]: If they have to wait that long to put men in, would some of those rascals have had it easy?
I don't know why.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I know I put a record on a lot of men way before I was.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had better record that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought to myself, it was all politics.
[SPEAKER_01]: Either give money, and I'll get it.
[SPEAKER_02]: But then we say, it's something we never do, because we were not well paid.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you've taken the older ballplayers, started their money, now it's on you.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know where we were.
[SPEAKER_00]: Somebody that we were talking to.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, some of the people don't even know anything about baseball before 1940.
[SPEAKER_00]: That somebody had sent him some old time to get him in the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, you know, with all these backs, oh, great job.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's what it was for.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you think Joe Wood should be in there?
[SPEAKER_00]: They were sending out trying to do whatever they knew.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I wish you'd have seen the paper.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, it was a long day.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, it was a long day.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, it was a long day.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, it was a long
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know how he's...
[SPEAKER_02]: I know he's about as good as Walter Johnson was.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_02]: I think he was.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was more wicked than Walter, because Walter had nothing but a fastball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Walter didn't have a curveball.
[SPEAKER_03]: If you couldn't see it, though, you couldn't hit it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Listen, you stood up there, Walter, you knew it was going to come with that play.
[SPEAKER_02]: You couldn't see it, could you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you could see it all right, but listen, you take Walter, if he had a curveball,
[SPEAKER_02]: a change of pace with that, there's nobody ever beat him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm telling you, nobody.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, Joe, he's wicked.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a good curveball.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was pretty near as fast as Walter.
[SPEAKER_03]: So.
[SPEAKER_03]: And what happened to him?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: He just hurt his arm, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because he come to Cleveland after that, and he played right field for us.
[SPEAKER_03]: He made quite a comeback.
[SPEAKER_02]: He tried to come back with his arm over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: He just goes so far, and that's all.
[SPEAKER_02]: Once you tear a ligament with two in your arm, it's not going to come back.
[SPEAKER_02]: You say one thing to a doctor, the doctor's not going to put new ligaments in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you've got a torn muscle, haven't you, or something?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, his muscle's down here someplace.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't have a muscle.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's down in here.
[SPEAKER_02]: But that's after baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: How about Walter Johnson as a teammate?
[SPEAKER_02]: The greatest man who ever lived.
[SPEAKER_02]: I know one time, when I was a white man, he didn't like to hunt.
[SPEAKER_02]: The water had a little farm someplace.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he told me, he says, Kofi, we're going to go out.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, I'm going out coon hunting tonight.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, that won't be in the morning.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, boy, some day you're going to get caught with your pants down.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, I know where I'm going.
[SPEAKER_02]: So the next morning, we're having a meeting, Bucky Harris looked over and he said, you're working for him.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he was out all night.
[SPEAKER_02]: He looked at me and started laughing.
[SPEAKER_03]: Probably pissed his shit out, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know what happened.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I know he was surprised with me.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, well, I don't want to go to pitch.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Bucky looked and said, you're working.
[SPEAKER_03]: Maybe Bucky Harris knew about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I don't think he knew about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He probably didn't know nothing about it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who else pitched on that Washington team in those years?
[SPEAKER_02]: Zachary.
[SPEAKER_03]: Tom Zachary.
[SPEAKER_03]: What's his other fellow's name?
[SPEAKER_03]: Marbury.
[SPEAKER_02]: A left-hander.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a left-hander at that time.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, he only carried, I think, six pitchers a day.
[SPEAKER_03]: 12 now, or 10 on a team.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think they spoil them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Long relievers or short relievers?
[SPEAKER_02]: The men that go in there, three or four in the gun barn, they get a hit or a run on, they pull them out.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know why they put a strange pitcher in.
[SPEAKER_03]: I can't see it.
[SPEAKER_03]: When you were playing, what about the strategy of having a right-handed hitter face a left-handed pitcher, and when they change pitchers, moving them around, you know, is there anything to that?
[SPEAKER_03]: Right-handed hitters hit left-handers better than they hit right-handed pitchers?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I think left-handed, I love to pick, I know them a lot in the hitter, but I love to hit again left-handed.
[SPEAKER_02]: So that gives the story.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had a right-hander and kept the ball away from me, where a left-hander, he'd throw a curve and come into me.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you ever hit a home run?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: What was your lifetime batting average?
[SPEAKER_02]: About a hundred.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll tell you the truth, I never tried to get on, unless I had to.
[SPEAKER_02]: One time I got on there, two out, I hit a double, and I'm more than second base,
[SPEAKER_02]: First ball of pitch, this fella hits it and puts him out.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now I'm walking, I'm out of wind running that far, and then I gotta walk to the bench and go out there and pitch.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I figured to myself, what the hell would you do?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do I have to?
[SPEAKER_02]: Other words, I don't want to even get on there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Would you just not swing at good pitches to not get on base?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, good pitch or something.
[SPEAKER_02]: I hit sometimes.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's because my eyes can hit them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, of course, they have courtesy runners for pitchers.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they're designated hitters, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Can you imagine, just because they're warming up, they have a cart to drive them to pitch?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: But aren't they cute little carts?
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd love to see the carts.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd like to have one.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm near dying.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's a lot of difference in baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: I could just imagine how you must think about it with all these changes.
I don't even want to.
[SPEAKER_00]: Once in a while, I want to.
[SPEAKER_03]: You read the sporting news?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I got that every day.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, that's declined, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: You don't have much baseball there.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I mean, your interest in baseball has... We can see the difference.
[SPEAKER_03]: It hasn't declined completely, though.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, some older players just...
[SPEAKER_02]: I just don't know what Bob did.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've only seen one ballgame in Chicago, and that's the closest place I've been since I was a little boy.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've got a lifetime passion.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've got a lifetime passion now.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've got a passion to take a party with you.
[SPEAKER_02]: I know I can do that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Mrs. Pontry.
[SPEAKER_02]: No crony here?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no crony.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think you're a crony, Senator.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I guess they must invite him.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he sent him over here.
[SPEAKER_01]: We got it done.
[SPEAKER_02]: We have one goal, wouldn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: To go and get that pie when he's still alive.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I couldn't see it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why should I go to Chicago?
[SPEAKER_01]: I go there to play a nice game.
[SPEAKER_02]: What time am I going to get home?
[SPEAKER_02]: Three, four o'clock in the morning?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I can't see it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you go to many football games here?
[SPEAKER_02]: I never go to any football games.
[SPEAKER_02]: I watch them and follow them on their football.
[SPEAKER_00]: I go on the lake fishing as well.
[SPEAKER_02]: I enjoy fishing better than anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: You went fishing today, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I didn't go fishing today.
[SPEAKER_00]: Your wives have still been with them, which has made it nice for them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because the weather's bad and they're not biting and it's supposed to be bad today.
[SPEAKER_03]: When you had a day off when you were playing, back in your playing days, did you go fishing then, if you could?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, if I was by somewhere, I would get there, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Plenty of golf?
[SPEAKER_01]: One time, if they didn't win, when he was pitching, as soon as you're talking to that guy, just keep your mouth shut.
[SPEAKER_03]: A little louder.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wants that.
[SPEAKER_03]: What was that again now?
[SPEAKER_01]: any time.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't win.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was no use talking to him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd just say, be quiet, I can't say nothing.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd be thinking where the mistake was.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: Those weren't very often, though, when he didn't win.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: One time, when, I don't know whether you were in the game at that time, Stan, when they brought those roses to you.
[SPEAKER_02]: Washington.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, some lady.
[SPEAKER_01]: So then the ballplayers, I was waiting for him, and the ballplayers were coming, and he just handed me that box.
[SPEAKER_01]: So they were saying, don't believe a word he says.
[SPEAKER_01]: You better just keep an eye on him.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I knew that it did bother me because I'm not jealous.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, isn't that something?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, you have some nice days, some sad days.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you take a picture of Mr. Kowalewski and I talking here?
[SPEAKER_01]: Sure.
[SPEAKER_03]: And we'd like to have one of you two together also.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he didn't stop.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you notice we're in our best bit back here, don't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I know.
[SPEAKER_02]: You're not taking that picture.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, I got a little pond in the back.
[SPEAKER_02]: A little what?
[SPEAKER_02]: A little fish pond.
[SPEAKER_02]: I keep my minnows in there all the time.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: Good.
[SPEAKER_03]: And how often do you go fishing?
[SPEAKER_03]: Every day.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: In the winter, he'd melt in twice, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you play any other sports either in school or
[SPEAKER_03]: How much schooling did you have?
[SPEAKER_02]: I went to work in the breakers when I was four years old.
[SPEAKER_03]: And you went to school up to that time?
[SPEAKER_02]: I put in kindergarten the first year, and he put me in second grade, and the same year he put me back in first grade.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was too small.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll do it with my glass here.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was your glass, right?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I kicked it over.
[SPEAKER_03]: Boy, I almost did.
[SPEAKER_03]: That would be you, wouldn't it?
Yeah, all right.
Did your brothers get any school, much schooling?
[SPEAKER_01]: Not much.
[SPEAKER_03]: You all had to go to work in the mines?
[SPEAKER_01]: Sure, everybody had to work.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sure, them days.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was your family into mining, too?
[SPEAKER_03]: My father was, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he died from miners' acid.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he was a sick man.
[SPEAKER_01]: What do you call that?
[SPEAKER_03]: Inhaling that coal?
[SPEAKER_01]: Black lung.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what they get money for.
[SPEAKER_03]: I thought there was another way to begin with.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know about that, but I know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because actually, although my husband teaches in Ohio, we live in West Virginia.
[SPEAKER_00]: We live across the river.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I mean, you know, you hear a lot about the black lung disease over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it's a wonder I haven't got it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, but all the dust.
[SPEAKER_00]: I left it back to you, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm telling you, I had a handkerchief when I started to work 7 o'clock in the morning and at night.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had a handkerchief during the day.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you couldn't see that far from dust and fire.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you make much money in baseball?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I guess one inch.
[SPEAKER_03]: Were you able to save much?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you couldn't save too much, but you could save some of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: You take a dollar then, it was only worth about 25 cents today.
[SPEAKER_03]: Let's see some of the showers they get today.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what he's asking.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because we were thinking about, you know, what these players get today.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're complaining about their pension plans.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're complaining about this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that's what he always says.
[SPEAKER_03]: You don't get any pension money at all, do you, from baseball?
[SPEAKER_03]: You get no pension from baseball at all.
[SPEAKER_01]: His whole heart and soul was in the game.
[SPEAKER_01]: He loved it so much.
[SPEAKER_03]: These modern players complain that they don't get enough.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, my God, look at that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Look at the commercials.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, absolutely.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, that's what I keep seeing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, yes, yes, that's true.
[SPEAKER_03]: Where did you stay in Cleveland when you were in the hotel?
[SPEAKER_03]: In Euclid.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you stay with them in Cleveland much?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, when I went down, yes, not too long.
[SPEAKER_02]: I stayed at the Euclid Hotel for a while.
[SPEAKER_02]: That one across from the cathedral, what's the name of that?
[SPEAKER_02]: I stayed at Wooden.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, that was an old time, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: How'd you like Leap Park to pitch in?
[SPEAKER_02]: I never played in Leap Park.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, Leap Park.
[SPEAKER_02]: I did.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I liked the pitch there.
[SPEAKER_03]: How about the short right field wall?
Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Listen, I seen them in Cleveland already on holidays.
[SPEAKER_02]: They have them, you know how short that field is.
[SPEAKER_02]: They have them lined up
[SPEAKER_02]: Six or seven in a line in front of that there.
[SPEAKER_03]: In front of the right field wall?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you were already starting to see a ball hitting there.
[SPEAKER_03]: It all went over.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, it wasn't over.
[SPEAKER_02]: It wasn't even hit that direction.
[SPEAKER_03]: When you were pitching, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, the other pitchers had done the same thing, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: I saw overflow crowds in left field, in front of the bleachers there, but never one in right field.
[SPEAKER_02]: You can make a hitter hit left field or right field.
[SPEAKER_03]: It didn't worry you to have a short field, did it?
[SPEAKER_02]: If you have control and keep that ball out there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, of course, you had that control and effectiveness.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's what I say.
[SPEAKER_02]: When Lee Parkman had them crowd there, he took a right-hander and kept hitting side on them.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the way.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, we hit that way, he don't hit it with my hand, and he didn't hit it with his crowd, anyhow.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the old thing of Pigeonism.
[SPEAKER_02]: You've got to know every hitter and what he can hit and what he can't hit.
[SPEAKER_02]: Another thing you've got to do, you've got to keep watching your outfield where they're playing.
[SPEAKER_02]: And make them hit where they're playing.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you have a pretty good memory of what every batter can do against you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Or do you have a book?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: I know that every man wants to come up there, what he can do against you.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then the catcher will help you out and hold that glove, give you a mark.
[SPEAKER_03]: Okay, let me just name a player now.
[SPEAKER_03]: Would it come back, do you think?
[SPEAKER_03]: Say somebody like Bob Musil.
[SPEAKER_03]: Would you know him?
[SPEAKER_03]: Of the Yankees?
[SPEAKER_03]: Mr. Musil?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, we know him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you kick that ball low outside.
[SPEAKER_02]: Listen, you kick the ball below the belt, where is he going to hit that ball?
[SPEAKER_02]: Not where is he going to hit.
[SPEAKER_02]: Once in a while, hey, Bob's going to get it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Eight out of ten shots, you're going to hit a line drive or you're going to hit a big run.
[SPEAKER_02]: When you keep it above the belt, what are you going to do with it?
[SPEAKER_02]: It's right in front of the lights coming there.
[SPEAKER_02]: A ball down low, you've got to look down at it.
[SPEAKER_02]: With a ball coming up, you look just like it's been left elevated.
[SPEAKER_00]: How much of your pictures do they have all that control?
[SPEAKER_00]: What's that?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't think the pictures today have that control.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: You have a straight overhand delivery?
[SPEAKER_02]: I threw a sidearm overhand.
[SPEAKER_02]: Would this be confused hitters, not knowing which was coming?
[SPEAKER_02]: If I was not hollow, I'd come straight over and hand it to them.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's just like me shooting a shotgun.
[SPEAKER_02]: I could throw the right one up straight like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's great.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did they always have the, at Lake Park, I'm thinking now, did they always have that screen in right field all the way over the scoreboard?
[SPEAKER_02]: I think that room pretty near the scoreboard.
[SPEAKER_03]: Anybody ever hit the scoreboard you ever saw?
[SPEAKER_03]: I never seen nobody hit the scoreboard.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's a long distance.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd be the best ballplayer you ever saw.
[SPEAKER_03]: Anybody stand out?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, they're all good ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_03]: Cobb stand out above Ruth?
[SPEAKER_02]: They're all good ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_02]: Cobb, he would, they probably better outfield him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Cobb is fast and all, and a good hitter, and that's what would overcome the outfield.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did Cobb try to hurt people on his flight?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't think he did, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't think he'd hurt anybody.
[SPEAKER_02]: I seen him one time in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: He come home and Steve O'Neal rocked him off.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he told Steve, he said, Steve, never stand in front of me again like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, and I don't want to come under my spikes high.
[SPEAKER_02]: The same game.
[SPEAKER_02]: He come in the same way and held it, and boy, hit spikes, hit Steve in the chest, and see how the green get patched up.
[SPEAKER_02]: But listen, there weren't one word said between both of them.
[SPEAKER_02]: He told them, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: All he said, give me one part of the plate.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's all he wanted, one part of the plate.
[SPEAKER_03]: Of course, the baseline belonged to the runner, and he was going to take that.
[SPEAKER_02]: But you say, well, he's catchy.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the plate.
[SPEAKER_02]: He'll come to the plate.
[SPEAKER_02]: You can get in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: But what are you going to do?
[SPEAKER_02]: Not you and me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd jump both feet right in his chest myself.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, and I think they all play for the love of the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, that's what seems to come through talking to the men.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wanted to ask you, what was life like being the wife of a great ball player?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, anytime he felt like going hunting, I never stood in his way.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's true.
[SPEAKER_01]: Never.
[SPEAKER_01]: And one thing he did say before he married me, he says, you know, I tune.
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, don't try to quit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Don't quit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Don't make me quit.
[SPEAKER_03]: That didn't last very long, though, did it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: He tuned.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't quit.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never tell him to.
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: He never stopped me from anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why should I stop him?
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, you can go to dances.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's no dancer.
[SPEAKER_01]: I used to go with my friends.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ain't that true, Colman?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, you don't go to see Notre Dame football though, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd rather go fishing.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's true.
[SPEAKER_02]: I enjoy fishing.
[SPEAKER_01]: You watch on TV sometimes.
[SPEAKER_02]: You go out there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't drive too much.
[SPEAKER_02]: You drive out there and all that traffic, and that traffic coming home.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he's been out at the games.
[SPEAKER_02]: I drive only at night.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't drive at night.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because I know I'm not the driver I used to be.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's true.
[SPEAKER_01]: When you get older, things go wrong.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're not as strong, I don't think.
[SPEAKER_01]: You see too much danger now with these colored people.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's just no fun.
[SPEAKER_03]: What was it like up in Cooperstown for the ceremonies there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, wonderful, wonderful.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I was nervous.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was my first experience.
[SPEAKER_01]: He got up.
[SPEAKER_01]: He couldn't get started.
[SPEAKER_01]: Good God, me sitting there wondering.
[SPEAKER_01]: So somebody come along, pat him on the back, and he started going, then he forgot where the period was.
[SPEAKER_01]: When he started, he forgot to quit.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he's no speech maker, but I'm not kidding.
[SPEAKER_02]: He told right away, he said, you know, I'm no speaker.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he says, by being a minor, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: He told that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And some people, when we were out at the table eating, there was two or three women come and congratulated him.
[SPEAKER_01]: But there was others came.
[SPEAKER_01]: But these three women, they must have had fathers that were minors.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'm not kidding you.
[SPEAKER_01]: They even tried.
[SPEAKER_01]: One thing I was proud of, he didn't have no paper written.
[SPEAKER_01]: Stan Musial got up.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had papers.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I thought, boy, that's big.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's true.
[SPEAKER_01]: He read off the papers.
[SPEAKER_00]: So have you gone back every year now?
[SPEAKER_01]: Every year so far, we've been going.
[SPEAKER_01]: Isn't that wonderful?
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you get flown up?
[SPEAKER_03]: They fly you up, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_01]: What?
[SPEAKER_03]: They fly you up to Utica or whatever?
[SPEAKER_01]: Utica.
[SPEAKER_03]: They have a car come and get you.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Last year, my son and the wife had driven up there, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, after the war, we'd come home with them, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: So we walked through Pennsylvania, my home town.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, and he took them to the mountains.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I don't know if he's going to help this year or not.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you don't know about this gas situation.
[SPEAKER_01]: You don't know from one day to another what you're going to hear.
[SPEAKER_02]: He even took me up in the mountains at our camps.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sure, where you used to be with Joe Wood.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you think Joe Wood would mind being interviewed?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he might be, but... Oh, I don't see... You'd have to ask him.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I hope he gets in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I hope he gets in.
[SPEAKER_02]: But they say you've got to be in there so many years.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wonder if I went up there with this tape recorder, do you think he'd object?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I don't think.
[SPEAKER_01]: He did it for Larry.
[SPEAKER_01]: What's his name?
[SPEAKER_01]: Ritter?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, is Ritter here?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's his picture there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: The glory of their time.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I wasn't home at the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: And another thing, last year was the first time that Larrick, so Coley, I guess he come over to Stan, he'd seen Stan, we shook hands with him, so Coley and him talked, but I'm with somebody else not paying any attention.
[SPEAKER_01]: So pretty soon this fella comes over and he says, can I sit down?
[SPEAKER_01]: I says, sure, you can.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a soul talk.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he says, do you come here every year?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, well, so far.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then he says, something about baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he says, about the player.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I says, I happen to be Mrs. Kowalewski.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then he says, I said, didn't you read about him?
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, no, I don't read the papers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, then I says, you don't know him.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he got scared for fear I'd open my big mouth and say something.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know how a woman gets rattled.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he said, he come over, and he says, you know who this is.
[SPEAKER_01]: And this guy is stepping aside of me all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he's nice looking, a friendly person.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I didn't do much talking.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was asking questions.
[SPEAKER_01]: So pretty soon, Colby comes over and he says, he's laughing like a rascal.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wonder, what's he laughing at?
[SPEAKER_01]: So he says, do you know who this guy is?
[SPEAKER_01]: I says, no, I don't know who he is.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm not smiling, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Only I felt, ain't that funny, asking me that, and then he don't read the papers?
[SPEAKER_01]: So when he says, Larry Ritter,
[SPEAKER_01]: if that floor would have opened up by the melt room.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, you don't know how I felt.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I apologized to him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, oh, you don't have to.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I kissed him.
[SPEAKER_01]: And oh my, he was, he sure, do you know him?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, never met him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he's a friendly guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he teaches at New York University.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he changed his address now, but he always wrote to us.
[SPEAKER_01]: So one time, see, I was working at the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cody went down when they advertised that book.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, Gloria, they're dying.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I didn't go.
[SPEAKER_01]: So Cody was down there, and he walked all over, dying for a chew.
[SPEAKER_01]: Couldn't buy any.
[SPEAKER_01]: So when Larry, he told me, when Larry come over, he says,
[SPEAKER_01]: place is this I Can Buy Chewtobacca.
[SPEAKER_01]: So Larry goes out and gets some Chewtobacca.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he's a grand guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wasn't there last year.
[SPEAKER_01]: A year before, that's when it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he always writes to us, Christmas.
[SPEAKER_01]: Always writes nice letters.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he did.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he's a nice-looking young man, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: It'd be great to be a nice-looking young man.
[SPEAKER_03]: Tell me, did you speak Polish at home?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm so broken.
[SPEAKER_03]: Nobody understands.
[SPEAKER_01]: But at home, at church.
[SPEAKER_03]: At home, we're broken.
[SPEAKER_03]: Mostly in English.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you speak Polish?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I can understand it, but I can't speak it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He chops it up.
[SPEAKER_02]: I understand it all.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did your parents speak it?
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm told.
[SPEAKER_03]: Were your parents speaking at home?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah, they spoke it.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I'm Polish.
[SPEAKER_02]: I can't speak Polish.
[SPEAKER_02]: I understand it, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And isn't it strange?
[SPEAKER_01]: People go to college to know different kind of languages.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you speak Polish?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I can.
[SPEAKER_02]: Polish, Slavish?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, my father and mother, they were Slavic.
[SPEAKER_01]: But there was no school in Shemogin, Slavic school.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he sent us to the Polish school.
[SPEAKER_01]: So then, I can speak it, but not as good as the Slavish people speak it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I can understand.
[SPEAKER_01]: But some words are pretty hard to understand.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because I have a sister, and she was married to a Slavish man.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's the only one I have left now, because they all passed away.
[SPEAKER_01]: And she lives in Uniontown, Pennsylvania, outside of Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_03]: You have a pretty big family, too?
[SPEAKER_01]: She had two boys and two girls.
[SPEAKER_01]: The one's an organist.
[SPEAKER_01]: The other one lives in Warren, Ohio.
[SPEAKER_01]: The nephew lives in Youngstown.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's the one that was sick, Ed.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the other boy lives around his mother's place.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was the religion play a pretty big part in your life back at home?
[SPEAKER_03]: Going to church, all of it?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you go to church?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, parents who stripped mine were, anyway.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know about his.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I guess they had to go to church.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's not like it was, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, the parents take over today.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was wondering about playing baseball on Sunday.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, that's the time they played.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the only time we had off.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's true.
[SPEAKER_03]: We were doing six days a week.
[SPEAKER_03]: Were you breaking the Sabbath though?
[SPEAKER_03]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: Were you violating the Sabbath by playing baseball on Sunday?
[SPEAKER_02]: Pennsylvania was a blue law.
[SPEAKER_02]: There was no baseball, but they couldn't stop the kids from, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, it's only not too long ago that Pennsylvania allowed baseball on Sundays.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, was you, were there any other cities in the league you couldn't play on Sunday in your time?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just Philadelphia?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, in Lancaster, we played them all, I guess, outside of...
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, we never played on Sundays.
[SPEAKER_02]: Never played on Sundays.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because I know I used to go home Saturday, Saturday after the game I'd go run home.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Monday morning I'd go back to Lancaster.
[SPEAKER_02]: I met him, but I don't know him.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a little later than the others.
[SPEAKER_01]: How many did you get already?
[SPEAKER_03]: About fifteen.
[SPEAKER_01]: Fifteen?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, George Yuley, Roger Peckinpah, Bill Womby, and not Womby.
[SPEAKER_03]: Womby doesn't want to... can't reach Womby.
[SPEAKER_01]: Womby?
[SPEAKER_01]: Does he live in Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Lives in Lakewood.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, he lives a few blocks from where I grew up.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, I did interview Wambi once when I was in junior high school, but I didn't know what to ask him.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he's not well now, and his wife is ill. Albert Smith told me this.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've been out in Cincinnati, I've talked to Larry Kopf, did you ever know him?
[SPEAKER_03]: He played in Cincinnati in 1919 in the World of Black Sox series.
[SPEAKER_03]: And a couple of other people who had very short careers in the big league, just a couple of years, and played minor league ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: And who else?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know, I just know the ones that I go to.
[SPEAKER_03]: Mickey Vernon.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's a more recent player, you know, Mickey Verne.
[SPEAKER_03]: His daughter was a student at Marietta, and so he's been there to see here, so I nailed him while he was there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm going to let that slip through my hands.
[SPEAKER_03]: So things like this.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I have here... You didn't get Harry Hoopman.
[SPEAKER_01]: It wasn't out of California.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm trying to get a grant.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, he's paying for all this himself.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm trying to get a grant from a group which gives money to people doing certain
[SPEAKER_03]: useful research projects to travel around the country and see people like Harry Hooper.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_03]: And California has so many of them, you know, old ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Texas and Florida, and it takes a lot of money to do that, so I'm going to try to get some funds to do this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Gee, that would be great.
[SPEAKER_03]: But here is a book which has the address, the name and address of every living ballplayer today in the country.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd like to get Yule's address.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who's?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yule.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I can give you that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because, you know, we didn't hear from him this Christmas, and I says, I wonder where's he at?
[SPEAKER_03]: Here it is right here, I think.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've got to get the pencil, don't I?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: 29925 Wolf Road, Bay Village.
[SPEAKER_03]: But it's organized by year in which you broke in.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, you'll be in 1912 here, because that was your, there you are.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's organized by the year in which they broke in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is there anybody else you'd like to know how they're, where they live now?
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd have to know their first year, but I didn't have to.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you know the spell of Canode?
[SPEAKER_03]: Canode?
[SPEAKER_03]: Kenneth Canode?
[SPEAKER_03]: This is in South Bend.
[SPEAKER_03]: He just had a very brief career.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know Ollie Behma?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh yeah, Ollie.
[SPEAKER_03]: I thought I'd go over and see him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that very hard to get to from here?
[SPEAKER_00]: Would you want this?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I'd love to.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, isn't that nice?
[SPEAKER_00]: Now I've got one.
[SPEAKER_02]: Hey, what's Ollie Behma's address down here?
[SPEAKER_02]: chestnut street.
[SPEAKER_01]: We'd have to open that telephone book.
[SPEAKER_03]: And George Uly is 29.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you get many kids wanting autographs?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: I bet you do.
[SPEAKER_03]: And pictures?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't think there's a day that I don't get one, two, or three.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: Do they send pictures?
[SPEAKER_02]: All kinds of pictures.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you have any pictures of yourself that you could spare?
[SPEAKER_02]: Or do you give them all away?
[SPEAKER_02]: What's that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Ask her.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't think there's any around.
[SPEAKER_02]: She may have some.
[SPEAKER_03]: You've probably given them all away, haven't you?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Every time they ask, he has her pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, you got one?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, do you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, with his address.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, his autograph.
[SPEAKER_03]: I want to take a picture of this.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is mine.
[SPEAKER_00]: You realize?
[SPEAKER_03]: Get him to autograph it, did he?
[SPEAKER_03]: It's autographed.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why I said, this one's mine.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I'd like to have one of those.
[SPEAKER_01]: Florida, because we go down there every year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, do you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Chamber of Commerce.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, you should see the people that come here to that banquet.
[SPEAKER_01]: This year they didn't, but they didn't say the reason.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I kind of think on account of the gas.
[SPEAKER_01]: Probably.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what it is.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is it St. Petersburg?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, Bradenton.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is it the Hall of Fame dinner?
[SPEAKER_01]: The Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I never seen no colored guy there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't see no colored guy being invited.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now that's an invitation.
[SPEAKER_02]: You want to know why I got any pictures now?
[SPEAKER_00]: Hidden pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well I tell you what he does, he takes them home sometimes and then has them copied and then he sends back the other ones.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well do you?
[SPEAKER_00]: You have a scrapbook?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you keep it?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did she keep it for you, or did you keep it?
[SPEAKER_02]: He did himself.
[SPEAKER_02]: I kept them myself.
[SPEAKER_03]: Most of the old players have their wives keep them for them.
[SPEAKER_02]: I kept all of these myself.
[SPEAKER_01]: These are pictures from Cooper's son.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know if that's what you... No, I thought they were pictures of me.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said he had spare copies that he might have in action.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, in action?
[SPEAKER_03]: You wouldn't have any more like that one, would you?
[SPEAKER_00]: playing around.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'll have to bring a camera.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm going to have some aid similar to that, and then I can send it to you if you want it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because I talked to this photographer down here, you know who, and she's in there all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm going to have to have some aid because I get too many calls.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: We gave quite a few pictures to Cooperston.
[SPEAKER_03]: Let me take a picture of this wall over here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now this is an old picture.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, him and, uh, what's his name?
[SPEAKER_00]: What's Harris?
[SPEAKER_00]: Harris.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's a good one, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's Harris.
[SPEAKER_00]: Which Harris is that?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who is that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, the Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who is that Harris?
[SPEAKER_00]: Didn't that say Harris?
[SPEAKER_00]: Ferris?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's with the Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: You don't know?
[SPEAKER_01]: You're shaking hands with them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, they come over and want a picture.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tell them what they're going to do.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh!
[SPEAKER_02]: Here's what I mean.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got two of these books.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: Beautiful.
[SPEAKER_03]: You mounted these all yourself, huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: You put these together all yourself?
[SPEAKER_03]: Let me take a closer look here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now see, here's a bunch of players.
[SPEAKER_01]: Lefty Groves, Ion, Jack Coombs, George, Irvin, Tim Shaw, Tim Wong, Irvin Faber, Gene Wendler, Walter Johnson here, Joe Bush, Colby,
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought maybe I had some.
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, that's that.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you want him alone, huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, yeah, if they had any spares, you know, that I could add to my collection.
[SPEAKER_03]: Something like that, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that'd be... Well, I'm gonna have some, and...
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd be very happy if you could...
[SPEAKER_00]: Now Jess Haynes was, he had, he didn't have any pictures left either, you know, I think he had one of himself.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he gave that one, he gave those to Gene, my husband, you know, and Gene took them back and took them to a photographer and had them copied.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he had an extra copy made for me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he sent back the original and the extra copy.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, because that's only fair if the man went his pictures to have them copied.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because that runs into money having pictures copied.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I do.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I know you do.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I've borrowed pictures and re-produced them.
[SPEAKER_03]: You ought to have that one.
[SPEAKER_03]: You ought to have copies made of this like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I'll have.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll have.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can look through this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, thank you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who is that?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's my nephew.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, your nephew.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's some of the guys that was at Cooperstown last year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Isn't that something?
[SPEAKER_01]: He's an editor or something out of that school.
[SPEAKER_01]: like Scranton paper.
[SPEAKER_01]: And this is Lee Morgan.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a good friend of Stan's.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's from Shmoopin.
[SPEAKER_01]: These are from Shmoopin.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's cool.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's taken in Cooperstown in Aruba when they were drinking.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh my.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got one.
[SPEAKER_01]: One cartoon, I don't know whose book it is.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's his wedding night.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, you're never going to see him.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's my oldest.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've ate Walter Johnson.
[SPEAKER_02]: Gosh, she's the only one that's celebrated.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've got a cast that's my version.
[SPEAKER_02]: Your version of Johnson?
[SPEAKER_00]: Isn't he a handsome Japanese?
[SPEAKER_01]: Isn't he a beautiful bride?
[SPEAKER_01]: She's a pretty girl.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh my, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Isn't he though?
[SPEAKER_01]: So there's some pictures that you want to look through.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, that's Paul Holland.
[SPEAKER_03]: Connie Mack praises you as the greatest except Walsh.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Marvel of control.
[SPEAKER_00]: Isn't he exactly?
[SPEAKER_02]: That was one of his trouble of control.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that's most people's biggest trouble.
[SPEAKER_03]: Guy Morton, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: He should have been a good pitcher, but he's too wild.
[SPEAKER_02]: He did a lot of stuff.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's too wild.
[SPEAKER_03]: How about George Yuley?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, he had good control.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had a couple of... he had health problems, though, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_03]: It seemed like every other year he was... his arm would go or something.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, he was... when I left there, he came in after I left.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was there probably a year before that.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was just a young fellow.
[SPEAKER_03]: Eddie Seacott, huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: What did you think about the Black Sox business?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you ever hear much about that?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Somebody called me up about Joe Jackson.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, they're all involved in it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I can tell you a story about how it started and all, but I wouldn't tell anybody.
[SPEAKER_02]: But someone wanted to know about Jackson, the story about Jackson.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, why about him?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, there are five others involved in it, so why don't you put them all in?
[SPEAKER_02]: Why pick on one?
[SPEAKER_03]: You don't want to tell the story?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I don't want to tell the story.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're not the tape recorder.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't want to tell what I think about them.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't want to tell it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I would be just about one man, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: Could I turn that off, would you tell the story?
[SPEAKER_03]: I turned it off, did you tell a story?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, that's something history would like to know about.
[SPEAKER_02]: I know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Why blame it on just one man, Joe Jackson?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, Jackson had a good series.
[SPEAKER_03]: He led both teams in hitting.
[SPEAKER_03]: I always felt that Jackson was
[SPEAKER_03]: He was kind of this farm boy who the gamblers took advantage of.
[SPEAKER_02]: He looked like a farm boy.
[SPEAKER_02]: I can't see why they should pick him up and the five or six others involved in the same thing.
[SPEAKER_03]: Would you object to Jackson getting in the Hall of Fame?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I think his record's good enough, but for the scandal I think he'd be in.
[SPEAKER_03]: This is a terrific scrapbook here.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'll have to come back with a camera.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I'm trying to get a camera that I can photograph your photographs and make copies that way.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's what I need.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because you have so many.
[SPEAKER_03]: Are there a lot of his playing career there?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, mostly that's all things.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that would be good.
[SPEAKER_03]: Boy, isn't that a great picture there?
[SPEAKER_01]: I found one.
[SPEAKER_03]: How's that?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, tremendous.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't suppose that's a spare copy, is it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Why don't you take it and have a copy and then you can send it back to them?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, would you?
[SPEAKER_03]: You can do that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Would you mind if I did?
[SPEAKER_03]: No!
[SPEAKER_01]: He can take it and then send it back to us.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, that'd be great.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that's the very, that's the very... We have pictures here, we have pictures there, and I'm housecleaning, see, so I don't know what happens.
[SPEAKER_03]: I could have a couple extra copies made of it, too, if you'd like to have a couple of spares to maybe send away or give away or something.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, listen, if you make pictures, we're willing to pay you for it.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, no, no, I'm not.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he doesn't make them himself.
[SPEAKER_00]: He has it done.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, but I wouldn't want you to do that, but I would...
[SPEAKER_01]: This is what I want made.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm going to have this made up down here.
[SPEAKER_03]: I could make just a few of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wouldn't be able to make them in large numbers like this man made.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: It'd just be three or four perhaps is all I could do.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, if you have to have them made, heavens.
[SPEAKER_01]: That runs into money.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, but I would want to make... Well, you can have that too.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then I'd want to send one back here to get it.
[SPEAKER_03]: autographed, so.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_03]: Went along with this one.
[SPEAKER_01]: I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: One about that size, one like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you want to keep for yourself?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that's what he said.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why couldn't he take a picture and go, we signed this now, then you just send the one back to us.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, it'd be a little hard to do.
[SPEAKER_03]: It'd work out okay.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd done this before.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_03]: With some things I had with Roger Peckinpah.
[SPEAKER_03]: that I've had copies and sent back.
[SPEAKER_03]: He signed them and sent them back, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'll put in the, he'll have the cardboard and everything and the envelope and the postage there so that all you have to do is stick it in.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some young man had sent us pictures here, Colby, like this.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, that was taken at Cooperstown, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: And the boys send it to us.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know how many he sent us.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was it three or four?
[SPEAKER_01]: My man always hates to smile.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: We have a son that hates to smile.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had one here standing near you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, my goodness.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was so angry and I said, my God, man, can't you think of something funny?
[SPEAKER_00]: We have a son who never smiles.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when his graduation pictures came back,
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, which one do you like?
[SPEAKER_00]: And there was one with just a faint hint of a smile.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, that's the one I like.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, you don't want that one, Mom.
[SPEAKER_00]: You don't want that one.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we have what he's...
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, you know, he's practically flowering.
[SPEAKER_03]: He doesn't realize what he does.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wish I had time to really read everything in him, is what I'd like to do, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's how much I enjoy going through these.
[SPEAKER_03]: But how was Bagby as a pitcher?
[SPEAKER_03]: He had one or two good years, but...
[SPEAKER_02]: He had good control, but he had a fadeaway, a good fadeaway.
[SPEAKER_03]: A fadeaway?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: We call it a spearball, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had really a good one.
[SPEAKER_02]: Really didn't break like a curveball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I have no big info.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he can put it in his briefcase, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, that's fine.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'll tell you, don't put it in the bottom of your suitcase then.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's great.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll hang that up in my office.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that's what he's got a base.
[SPEAKER_00]: He has an office over at the college and he's got baseball pictures in it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I got him a great big plastic baseball and he's got that hanging down from the middle of the ceiling.
[SPEAKER_00]: Big balloon that looks like a baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, Iza, if I get all this coffee, then... No, no, no, really, no, we've got to go.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, we've got to go.
[SPEAKER_00]: We don't want to wear you out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not you, I'm not asking you.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, you've had your quota for the day.
[SPEAKER_03]: How about a little picture of you two sitting together on the couch, and looking through the scrapbook, how'd that be?
[SPEAKER_01]: I look like a skinned off rabbit, with my hair straight back.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't care what I look like.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you want me to tell you one of them?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And here, I'll give you this.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's all right.
[SPEAKER_02]: It'll be broken.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, and then he'll send you a copy of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Don't get them too close, because I got a big nose.
[SPEAKER_03]: Here, look through the scrapbook.
[SPEAKER_03]: Fine.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because you sent pictures to the Haynes' and that, didn't you, the pictures we took of them?
[SPEAKER_00]: And sicking, and so forth and so on.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then they won't see your face.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't want them to.
[SPEAKER_01]: Smile, Pop.
[SPEAKER_03]: Very good.
[SPEAKER_01]: I broke the glass.
[SPEAKER_01]: This has been great.
[SPEAKER_03]: We got almost another cider almost.
[SPEAKER_03]: We'll have to get going.